[Music]
does use of alternative medicine in
addition to Conventional therapies
predict prolonged survival from cancer I
mean even if alternative therapies
themselves were useless one might
predict users would live longer because
they tend to have more hope a greater
will to live nearly three times as
likely to believe their cancer was
curable even if it wasn't but death
rates were actually higher in
alternative medicine users followed them
up years later and 79% of the
alternative medicine users had died
compared to 65% of non-users now if the
alternative medicine users started out
sicker that could certainly explain it
and they did tend to be though the
difference didn't reach statistical
significance uh bottom line the
association between the use of
alternative medicine and shortened
survival is not necessarily cause and
effect but it's possible some of the
alternative modalities may have indeed
been
harmful thanks to the internet there's
been a Resurgence of older complimentary
and alternative Cancer Treatments such
as leil which is a compound derived from
aalin a natural cyanide containing
substance concentrated in apricot
kernels the seeds inside the
pits it was branded as a vitamin to
skirt regulations vitamin B17
but it's not a vitamin and the lack of
Lil's Effectiveness against cancer and
the risk of side effects from cyanide
poisoning led to its being banned
decades ago however no surprise you can
still buy it on the internet along with
the apricot kernels themselves why not
just give them a try though because of
cyanide intoxication here's a typical
case report a woman ate some abcot seeds
she got at a health food store so hey
they got to be healthy right 20 minutes
later she was having trouble breathing
before she slipped into a coma they made
some calculations and it appears an 8 O
bag of apricot kernels is enough to kill
six people if consumed in one city
therefore the continuing sale of apricot
kernels as health food is
troubling and you never know what you're
getting here this person was consuming a
quarter of a teaspoon of ground apricot
Colonels daily and had just switched
Brands the day before she ended up in
the ICU thankfully she survived others
are not so lucky like this
17-year-old who was dead within a day as
severe cyanide poisoning can result in
coma convulsions and cardiovascular
collapse that's why calling it a vitamin
is so Insidious 32-year-old woman
arrives at emergency room in a coma was
she on anything no she she just took
some vitamin supplements thankfully a
relative showed up with them oh B17 they
gave her a cyanide antidote and she
survived but had that relative not
showed up or been delayed in traffic or
something the case could have proved
fatal so cancer patients should be
informed about the high risk of
developing serious adverse effects due
to cyanide poisoning after Lil or
amygdalin natural compound in apricot
seeds especially at risk may be those
taking Mega doses of Vitamin C or those
not getting enough vitamin B12 see the
body has two major ways to detoxify
cyanide it can attach it to B12 to form
the supplement form cyanic balment which
can then be harmlessly peed out or it
can use the amino acid cysteine which is
also used to metabolize vitamin C and so
if you take too much vitamin C levels
can drop and you can end up more
vulnerable to cyanine
toxicity but hey conventional cancer
treat such as chemo can be toxic too
it's all about benefits versus risks
yeah amygdalin can block the growth of
certain cancer cells in a Petri dish
though doesn't appear to have any
anti-cancer effects against laboratory
animal tumors U but you don't know what
happens in people until you put it to
the test and do a clinical trial of
amygdalin in the treatment of human
cancer which will cover
next
[Music]